Now we're going to cover the ITTOs of
communication management.
So I do recommend again that you follow
along in the PIMBOC.
So plan communication management,
the ITTOs.
So we need to ensure that the stakeholder
information needs are met.
So we'll plan communications.
Who needs what, when, where, why,
how.
Think journalism.
We'll plan communications to the
stakeholder engagement together.
actually.
So our inputs, these are at a higher
level.
The Charter has any of our high-level
stakeholders, key stakeholders,
at least you and the sponsor are in there,
any other key stakeholders we know about.
Project management
plan comes in, we'll plan
stakeholder engagement
and communications together.
So the first go-around, we wouldn't have a
lot of these plans and documents.
E-EFs and OPAs will keep coming in.
Tools and techniques will use expert
judgment.
We'll figure out the communication
requirements of each of our stakeholders,
which communication technology we will
use.
You have to think about
the project environment,
whether we're all co-located
or virtual, spread out.
We'll use our five steps in the
communication model covered in an upcoming
slide, as well as our communication
methods.
Interactive, push and push.
Those are coming up too.
And as always, because we're
dealing with stakeholders, we
use those interpersonal
and team skills, our soft skills.
We'll do the communication
styles assessment,
use political awareness
and cultural awareness.
They go hand in hand.
We'll also be looking at that stakeholder
engagement assessment matrix.
So you can find that in your PIMBAC.
I will cover that in the stakeholder
knowledge area.
But it will determine the level of
communication.
each stakeholder needs.
And of course, we're having a planning
meeting.
So every time you plan, you always at
least produce a plan.
We just plan communication management, we
produce our communication management plan.
Defining how we will do our communication
processes.
Later, if our plans approach a strategy or
any of the documents have to change
through a change request, we'll update
plans and documents accordingly.
Once we're baseline, otherwise as we keep
planning, we'll keep updating.
So you have to know whether or not you are
baselined.
If we're not baselines, you keep planning.
You update plans and documents along the
way.
Once we're baseline, any plan and document
updates will require a change request.
Alright, now we move over into executing.
Now we're doing the work of the project.
and our baseline.
This is where we'll communicate.
We're doing the work of the project
according to the plan.
So we will create,
collect, distribute relevant
information to the
appropriate stakeholders.
Our inputs, the project management plan.
Stakeholder and communication management
plans unbelievably intertwined.
Again, think journalism.
Who needs what, when, where, why,
how?
Project documents.
that change in issue log.
This is where we're
going to communicate the
disposition of the change
requests and that issue log.
Then big work performance
reports that come
from monitor and control the project work.
Remember, this contains
all the project information,
progress from all our
controlling processes.
So again, we send out work performance
reports right here in this process.
They are used to raise awareness,
take action, and make decisions.
This is where we'll communicate those out.
Then, of course, you have those EEFs and
OPAs.
The tools and techniques, verbs, we'll use
the communication
technology that we planned.
We'll use our communication methods.
We'll use our communication skills like
communication competencies, getting
feedback, ensuring the stakeholders
understand the communications,
including watching them.
Watching that body language, facial
expressions, and we'll give presentations.
We'll use PMIS, of course.
This is where we will actually do our
project reporting.
We will use those interpersonal and team
skills.
Oh, so important.
Active listening, ensuring whoever we're
communicating with.
We're listening.
Repeat back.
We'll manage conflict, use cultural and
political.
Critical awareness, we'll again manage
meetings and networking.
Best way to communicate as we're having
our meetings, of course.
So big the outputs, the project
communications.
Along the way, we'll update plans and
documents through change requests.
We're baselined when we move into
executing and we'll update our OPAs.
We've been pulling from them this whole
time.
we contribute to them as well.
ITTOs and monitor project communications.
We're monitoring the communications.
Are the stakeholders getting what they
need, when they need it, how they wanted it.
So our inputs are planned, communications
and stakeholder engagement, big pieces
again, project documents, the issue log,
and the communications.
Data, as with every other controlling
process, we compare the plan, what was
agreed to upon to the data, what's
actually happening.
We're looking for variants.
Those EEFs and OPAs keep coming in as
well.
Tools and techniques will use expert
judgment and our PMIS.
We will again look at that stakeholder
engagement assessment matrix.
We should see where the current engagement
levels matches the desired meaning our
communications are working involving the
stakeholders in our project communicating,
are getting them to support the project,
lead the project.
And of course we'll use those
interpersonal team skills like observation
watching them and talking to them,
of course.
Our outputs, like every other controlling
process, your plan and data come in,
information goes out.
That's the progress with the
communications.
If we are not progressing as planned,
that will require a change request.
We're definitely baselined.
So if that change request is approved,
we update plan strategies, baselines,
and project documents accordingly.